<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">34544506 autoKernelBuildLogbook</title>
<updated>2022-02-28T12:00:00Z</updated>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MrMairey/autoKernelBuild/main/logbook.xml"/>
<id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MrMairey/autoKernelBuild/main/logbook.xml</id>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MrMairey/autoKernelBuild/main/logbook.xml"/>
<entry>
	<title>2022-03-18 | Week 8</title>
	<updated>2022-03-18:00:00Z</updated>
	<published>2022-03-21:00:00Z</published>
	<content type="html">
		<![CDATA[
<p> Week 8 Log </p>

<p> On Tuesday 15th of March, I made further progress on documentation and the presentation </p>

<p> Next week I hope to add the function to read kernel .config files from /proc/config.gz and supplied .config files </p>
	]]>
</content>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>2022-03-11 | Week 7</title>
<updated>2022-03-11:00:00Z</updated>
<published>2022-03-14:00:00Z</published>
<content type="html">
	<![CDATA[ <p> Fifth logbook post </p>
<p> Week 7 Log </p>
<p> On Friday 11th March I worked on the documentation as well as simplifying the proprosal presentation. </p>
<p> Next week I hope to add the function to read kernel .config files from /proc/config.gz and supplied .config files </p>
]]>
</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<title>2022-02-25 | Week 6</title>
<updated>2022-03-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
<published>2022-03-07T00:00:00Z</published>
<content type="html">
	<![CDATA[ <p> Fourth logbook post </p>

<p> Week 6 Log </p>
<p> On tues 1st march I moved the KERNDIR code i added from last week. Also I added some code to interpret options and arguments, still needs a bit of work. Grouped sections of program into subprograms/modules. </p>
<p> On wed 2nd march I added the prompt to obtain a kernel version from the user and saved it as a variable, additionally I added code to allow for kernel versions other than v5.x.x to be used. Later that afternoon I made some revisions to the download system, fixing POSIX shell compatibility and debloating code</p>
<p>Next week I will polish code, apply teacher's feedback to powerpoint/proposal and add the placeholders for the user queries.</p>
]]>
</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<title>2022-02-25 | Week 5</title>
<updated>2022-02-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
<published>2022-02-28T00:00:00Z</published>
<content type="html">
	<![CDATA[ <p> Third logbook post

On Wednesday 23rd Feb I created the directory tree diagram in lucidchart. Next week hope to apply the dir tree as commands in the program.
Next week I will polish code, apply teacher's feedback to powerpoint/proposal and add the placeholders for the user queries.</p>]]>
</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<title>2022-02-18 | Week 4</title>
<updated>2022-02-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
<published>2022-02-21T00:00:00Z</published>
<content type="html">
	<![CDATA[ <p>The second RSS Feed / logbook post</p> <p>On samonday (14th) I created the autoKern file (the actual script) and coded the very basic commands used for the kernel build process. <p> Wednesday (16th) I added alternative commands for the option of verbose output. Obtained feedback from teacher, three main points were: </p>
		<p> 1. define a particular group that the project aims at for end users, and obtain an interview transcript with end users to further discern program requirements </p>
		<p> 2. Adjust project proposal to allow for a simpler understanding of technical jargon and processes </p>
		<p> 3. Film and share a video demo of the final product of the program to demonstrate usage and screen layout </p>
		<p> Thursday (17th) I then added a function to silence the program's output, however I am not super happy with the way this was executed, and will hopefully revise this system. Friday (18th) I modified the code to account for kernel versions and (some) file overwrites, there is a bit more that needs to be done in this area as some conflicts will still occur, but the idea is there and it works fine in most situations. </p>
		<p>Next week I hope to create the directory tree diagram, polish the code a bit and apply teacher's feedback to the powerpoint/proposal </p>]]>
</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<title>2022-02-11 | Week 3</title>
<updated>2022-02-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
<published>2022-02-14T00:00:00Z</published>
<content type="html">
	<![CDATA[ <p>The first RSS Feed / logbook post</p> <p> On sunday and saturday (february 12th and 13th) I will be working on the Major Project Proposal presentation. Today (11th) I am writing the text for the rss feed / logbook to be published when I create the git repo and RSS feed during week 4.</p>]]>
</content>
</entry>
