<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">34544506 autoKernelBuildLogbook</title>
<updated>2022-05-13T12:00:00Z</updated>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MrMairey/autoKernelBuild/main/logbook.xml"/>
<id>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MrMairey/autoKernelBuild/main/logbook.xml</id>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MrMairey/autoKernelBuild/main/logbook.xml"/>

<entry>
	<title>2022-05-13 | Week 3 Term 2</title>
	<updated>2022-05-13:00:00Z</updated>
	<published>2022-05-16:00:00Z</published>
	<content type="html">
		<![CDATA[
		<p> Term 2 Week 3 Log </p>
<p> On Saturday 7th of May, I fixed various typos as well as removed the functions regarding silent mode as it was causing issues and needed to be revised at a later date. </p>
<p> On Sunday 8th of May, I modified the subprogram names as they were conflicting with sections of code and causing code loops. Additionally, I added the code to update the bootloader and fixed a few typos. </p>
<p> On Monday 9th of May, I added functions to check the system for the necessary dependencies along with a few typos. Later that day, more dependencies were added, more typos were fixed, indents were modified and the getopts (get options) section was moved. Furthermore, I wrote the manual page and added code to interpret it. </p>
<p> On Tuesday 10th of May, the dependency list was updated and the code was given a general clean which found a few typos. Additionally, I set up a virtual machine to test the program in, which will also be used to film the demonstration video. </p>
<p> On Thursday 12th of May bugfixes were applied regarding the getopts section of code, as well as adding the functions to install the latest kernel version or to install a kernel version specified with -k. </p>
<p> On Friday 13th of May, certain areas of code were modified to ensure the program exited when intended, such as at errors. Additionally, portions of code were substituted for subprograms and vice versa. </p>
<p> Next week I hope to make significant progress on documentation, fix the silent function, implement an architecture compatibility check and create the framework for the configuration file. </p>
]]>
</content>
</entry>

<entry>
	<title>2022-05-06 | Week 2 Term 2</title>
	<updated>2022-05-06:00:00Z</updated>
	<published>2022-05-09:00:00Z</published>
	<content type="html">
		<![CDATA[
			<p> Week 2 Term 2 </p>
<p> On Thursday 5th of May I added a function to obtain the latest kernel version if the user enters nothing in the KERNVER prompt </p>
<p> On Friday 6th of May I removed the cleaned the code by removing the preMake function which only contained a single command </p>
<p> Next week I hope to apply bug fixes, add a dependency check, start on the help page and make further progress with documentation </p>
]]>
</content>
</entry>


<entry>
	<title>2022-04-29 | Week 1 Term 2</title>
	<updated>2022-05-02:00:00Z</updated>
	<published>2022-05-02:00:00Z</published>
	<content type="html">
		<![CDATA[
		<p> Week 1 Term 2</p>
<p> On Tuesday 26th of April I made an adjustment to the directory where the program will perform it's operations. </p>
<p> Additionally, I made changes to the variable declaration code to ensure that they are readable by every subprogram </p>
<p> On Wednesday 27th of April I obtained feedback on my associated documentation which I hope to apply Monday of next week </p>
<p> Next week I hope to make further progress with the program, as well as associated documentation. </p>
]]>
</content>
</entry>


<entry>
	<title>2022-04-22 | Holiday Week 2</title>
	<updated>2022-04-25:00:00Z</updated>
	<published>2022-04-25:00:00Z</published>
	<content type="html">
		<![CDATA[
		<p> Holiday Week 2 Logbook Post</p>
		<p> On Wednesday 20th of April I made further progress with associated documentation. </p>
		<p> On Friday 22nd of April I made some tweaks to the presentation </p>
		<p> Next week I hope to make further progress with the program, as well as making further progress with documentation </p>
]]>
</content>
</entry>


<entry>
	<title>2022-04-15 | Holiday Week 1</title>
	<updated>2022-04-18:00:00Z</updated>
	<published>2022-04-19:00:00Z</published>
	<content type="html">
		<![CDATA[
		<p> Holiday Week 1 Logbook Post</p>
<p> On Thursday 14th of April I made further progress with associated documentation. </p>
<p> Next week I hope to make further progress with the program, as well as making further progress with documentation </p>
]]>
</content>
</entry>

<entry>
	<title>2022-04-08 | Week 11</title>
	<updated>2022-04-11:00:00Z</updated>
	<published>2022-04-12:00:00Z</published>
	<content type="html">
		<![CDATA[
		<p> Week 11 Logbook Post</p>
<p> On Friday 8th of April I added a section to handle kernel configuration files as well as fixing a typo. </p>
<p> Additionally I made further progress with associated documentation. </p>
<p> Next week I hope to make further progress with the program's sequences, as well as making further progress with documentation </p>
]]>
		</content>
</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2022-04-01 | Week 10</title>
	<updated>2022-04-04:00:00Z</updated>
	<published>2022-04-04:00:00Z</published>
	<content type="html">
		<![CDATA[
	<p> On Wednesday 30th of March I made further progress on associated documentation. </p>
	<p> Next week I hope to make further progress with making the program's sequence functional as well as amking further progress with documentation. </p>
	]]>
</content>
</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2022-03-25 | Week 9</title>
	<updated>2022-03-25:00:00Z</updated>
	<published>2022-03-28:00:00Z</published>
	<content type="html">
		<![CDATA[
<p> Week 9 Logbook Post </p>
<p> On Friday 25th of March I added a section of code to run the subprograms that I had initially only created and declared </p>
<p> The code has some bugs that need to be fixed before it runs properly, will likely work on getting fully working code next week </p>
<p> Additionally, next week I hope to continue with associated documentation. </p>
	]]>
</content>
</entry>
<entry>
	<title>2022-03-18 | Week 8</title>
	<updated>2022-03-18:00:00Z</updated>
	<published>2022-03-21:00:00Z</published>
	<content type="html">
		<![CDATA[
<p> Week 8 Log </p>

<p> On Tuesday 15th of March, I made further progress on documentation and the presentation </p>

<p> Next week I hope to add the function to read kernel .config files from /proc/config.gz and supplied .config files </p>
	]]>
</content>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>2022-03-11 | Week 7</title>
<updated>2022-03-11:00:00Z</updated>
<published>2022-03-14:00:00Z</published>
<content type="html">
	<![CDATA[ <p> Fifth logbook post </p>
<p> Week 7 Log </p>
<p> On Friday 11th March I worked on the documentation as well as simplifying the proprosal presentation. </p>
<p> Next week I hope to add the function to read kernel .config files from /proc/config.gz and supplied .config files </p>
]]>
</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<title>2022-02-25 | Week 6</title>
<updated>2022-03-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
<published>2022-03-07T00:00:00Z</published>
<content type="html">
	<![CDATA[ <p> Fourth logbook post </p>

<p> Week 6 Log </p>
<p> On tues 1st march I moved the KERNDIR code i added from last week. Also I added some code to interpret options and arguments, still needs a bit of work. Grouped sections of program into subprograms/modules. </p>
<p> On wed 2nd march I added the prompt to obtain a kernel version from the user and saved it as a variable, additionally I added code to allow for kernel versions other than v5.x.x to be used. Later that afternoon I made some revisions to the download system, fixing POSIX shell compatibility and debloating code</p>
<p>Next week I will polish code, apply teacher's feedback to powerpoint/proposal and add the placeholders for the user queries.</p>
]]>
</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<title>2022-02-25 | Week 5</title>
<updated>2022-02-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
<published>2022-02-28T00:00:00Z</published>
<content type="html">
	<![CDATA[ <p> Third logbook post

On Wednesday 23rd Feb I created the directory tree diagram in lucidchart. Next week hope to apply the dir tree as commands in the program.
Next week I will polish code, apply teacher's feedback to powerpoint/proposal and add the placeholders for the user queries.</p>]]>
</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<title>2022-02-18 | Week 4</title>
<updated>2022-02-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
<published>2022-02-21T00:00:00Z</published>
<content type="html">
	<![CDATA[ <p>The second RSS Feed / logbook post</p> <p>On samonday (14th) I created the autoKern file (the actual script) and coded the very basic commands used for the kernel build process. <p> Wednesday (16th) I added alternative commands for the option of verbose output. Obtained feedback from teacher, three main points were: </p>
		<p> 1. define a particular group that the project aims at for end users, and obtain an interview transcript with end users to further discern program requirements </p>
		<p> 2. Adjust project proposal to allow for a simpler understanding of technical jargon and processes </p>
		<p> 3. Film and share a video demo of the final product of the program to demonstrate usage and screen layout </p>
		<p> Thursday (17th) I then added a function to silence the program's output, however I am not super happy with the way this was executed, and will hopefully revise this system. Friday (18th) I modified the code to account for kernel versions and (some) file overwrites, there is a bit more that needs to be done in this area as some conflicts will still occur, but the idea is there and it works fine in most situations. </p>
		<p>Next week I hope to create the directory tree diagram, polish the code a bit and apply teacher's feedback to the powerpoint/proposal </p>]]>
</content>
</entry>

<entry>
<title>2022-02-11 | Week 3</title>
<updated>2022-02-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
<published>2022-02-14T00:00:00Z</published>
<content type="html">
	<![CDATA[ <p>The first RSS Feed / logbook post</p> <p> On sunday and saturday (february 12th and 13th) I will be working on the Major Project Proposal presentation. Today (11th) I am writing the text for the rss feed / logbook to be published when I create the git repo and RSS feed during week 4.</p>]]>
</content>
</entry>
